058-458-6484 (Israel) 201-994-6484 (US) ari.abramowitz1@gmail.com

Ari Abramowitz Full Stack Web Developer

ariabr.netlify.app linkedin.com/in/ariabr github.com/ariabr

Summary

Full stack web developer and team lead experienced in both startup and agile environments. I am a creative and methodical problem solver with strong writing skills and a background in philosophy. I am always ready for a new challenge and the opportunity to bring another product to life.

Skills

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Backend / Databases: Python, Django, Flask, Node, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Express, Firebase

Other Tools: Git, GitHub, Bash, Heroku, Jasmine, Pytest, Jira, Trello

Experience

Software Team Lead | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions

2023 - Present

- · Managed team of engineers in completing software projects
- · Contributed to the process of transforming business requirements into actionable tickets
- · Mentored team members on software development practices

Fullstack Software Engineer | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions

2020 - Present

- · Approved and deployed code across 15+ projects
- · Developed software to streamline AR management for 80,000+ residents in 80 facilities throughout the US
- · Improved efficiency of lab processing 2,000+ COVID tests per day by building an app to track sample history
- · Improved code quality by performing initial and final code reviews for a team of 10 developers
- · Wrote clear and detailed documentation to ease future development

Software Developer | Taryag Analytics

2019 - 2020

- · Primary developer for a text mining and analytics startup
- Enabled 2020 Q1 beta launch by developing the frontend and backend for 6 new analysis features, including a sentence structure analyzer, a word cloud generator, and multiple text comparison tools
- · Improved comparative analysis capabilities by building a web-scraping ETL process to load new source data

Powered by Sefaria Contest

2020

- · Frontend developer for team building a 3D family tree visualizer for the Powered by Sefaria contest
- · Awarded Honorable Mention and featured as a showcase project on the company's website

The Ezrat Nashim Database

2018 - Present

· Designed and developed crowdsourced website to aid users in assessing local synagogue options

Open-Source Contributions

•	Django Easy Aud	lit: Coded bug fix for d	atabase auditing package v	with 6,000+ weekly downloads	2022
	3.61 1C 1.7	77 79 16 . 11	. (1)		0000

Mindful Internet Use: Fixed frontend bug in Chrome productivity extension with 1,000+ users
2020

Education

Continuing Education

continuing Databation				
· Bash Mastery: The Complete Guide to Bash Shell Scripting (Ziyad Yehia, Udemy)	2021			
· Test-Driven Development with Python (Harry Percival)	2021			
· The Ultimate Java Mastery Series (Code with Mosh)	2020			

Bloc | Web Developer Track

2019

- · Built 5 cloud-hosted web-apps as part of an 8-month apprentice-style coding bootcamp
- Mastered fundamental principles of software engineering and web development through project-based learning

Rutgers University | BA | Summa Cum Laude | GPA: 3.94

2018

- · Majors: Philosophy, Jewish Studies; Minor: Religion
- · Semester Abroad: Honors Program, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- · Honor societies: Phi Beta Kappa; Natl. Society of Collegiate Scholars; Natl. Society of Leadership and Success